<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J Rave</title>
    <link>https://jrave.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on J Rave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 J Rave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 23:52:46 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jrave.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brain Dump: Dialogue vs Conversation in Textile</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/blog/dialogue_4-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 23:52:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/blog/dialogue_4-23/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll try to reign this in as much as possible. Bear in mind this is somewhere between a design doc and a stream of consciousness.
Dialogue trees would be a wild way to speak to another human being. And yet, they&amp;rsquo;re ubiquitous in the world of video games.
They give the player ultimate agency over the information given in an interaction. The best dialogue systems in this style make it clear when a given option will move the conversation forward and give the player necessary information, or when it will give the player additional non-vital details.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try to reign this in as much as possible. Bear in mind this is somewhere between a design doc and a stream of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dialogue-trees-would-be-a-wild-way-to-speak-to-another-human-being&#34;&gt;Dialogue trees would be a wild way to speak to another human being.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, they&amp;rsquo;re ubiquitous in the world of video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They give the player ultimate agency over the information given in an interaction. The best dialogue systems in this style make it clear when a given option will move the conversation forward and give the player necessary information, or when it will give the player additional non-vital details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players need to buy in and voluntarily get more out of a conversation, or otherwise can breeze through an interaction and get back to the gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-can-we-do-better&#34;&gt;How can we do better?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When conversation &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; gameplay, simply following the heuristic isn&amp;rsquo;t nearly good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a visual novel, roleplaying game, or social deduction game, some of the most important gameplay revolves around speaking to the game&amp;rsquo;s characters. More importantly, &lt;em&gt;listening&lt;/em&gt; to them. But we&amp;rsquo;re still stuck on the rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick is to move away from the idea of dialogue, and toward conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-the-difference&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dialogue is performance. It exists for the benefit of an audience. Using a typical dialog tree, the player might be able to direct how much of a dialogue they see, or whether they see the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; version of the dialogue, but regardless they&amp;rsquo;ll be fed similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversation is a living thing. It exists for the benefit of its participants. In this case, both the player and the NPC would exchange information. What a character knows will be affected by what the player divulges, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-no-dialogue&#34;&gt;So, no dialogue?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes dialogue! But in Textile, we must make a distinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversation: Interaction between the player and one or more characters, driven systemically by character knowledge and motivation as well as player input. Mushroom and/or venom writing, per Emily Short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dialogue: Written exchange between two or more characters. Highly curated or non-generated; beeswax writing, per Emily Short.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/about/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/about/hello/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a game developer, software engineer, and all-around pusher of buttons.
My work is mainly in C/C++, with a healthy dose of other languages. I make games and tools for game developers.
I live in the Midwest US, where I grew up. I&amp;rsquo;m an agender person (they/them), a Zen Buddhist, and a hobbyist musician / cook / linguist / all sorts of things.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a game developer, software engineer, and all-around pusher of buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work is mainly in C/C++, with a healthy dose of other languages. I make games and tools for game developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in the Midwest US, where I grew up. I&amp;rsquo;m an agender person (they/them), a Zen Buddhist, and a hobbyist musician / cook / linguist / all sorts of things.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m J. This is a website.</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/frontpage/frontpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/frontpage/frontpage/</guid>
      <description>I write software and make games, and I like to think I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it. I&amp;rsquo;m currently employed at Torn Banner Studios.
Check the links above for more about me and my professional work, my personal dev blog, and other ways to find me online.
✌ </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I write software and make games, and I like to think I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it. I&amp;rsquo;m currently employed at &lt;a href=&#34;https://tornbanner.com&#34;&gt;Torn Banner Studios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the links above for more about me and my professional work, my personal dev blog, and other ways to find me online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;✌&lt;/h1&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/about/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/about/projects/</guid>
      <description>Textile Very early work-in-progress. An engine-agnostic framework for systematic narrative games, plus an editor for narrative content. This is my current passion project.
The goal of Textile is to create narrative experiences with nuance, where both writers and players have more agency to make creative choices.
Textile is being developed alongside another personal project, a yet-unannounced narrative game.
Torn Banner Studios I&amp;rsquo;m currently employed here as a Tools Programmer. No details to share just yet!</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;textile&#34;&gt;Textile&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Very early work-in-progress.&lt;/em&gt; An engine-agnostic framework for systematic narrative games, plus an editor for narrative content. This is my current passion project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Textile is to create narrative experiences with nuance, where both writers and players have more agency to make creative choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Textile is being developed alongside another personal project, a yet-unannounced narrative game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;torn-banner-studios&#34;&gt;Torn Banner Studios&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently employed here as a Tools Programmer. No details to share just yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;saints-row-2022&#34;&gt;Saints Row (2022)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first shipped AAA title - I worked on this from pre-production to DLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The realtime cinematics system was &lt;em&gt;my baby&lt;/em&gt;. In addition to implementing anything the cinematic artists needed, I also heavily supported the good folks in the lighting, VFX, and audio teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also the sole dedicated accessibility programmer, so I owned features like alternative control methods, blood &amp;amp; gore, subtitles, and some challenge level settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;volitions-ctg-editor&#34;&gt;Volition&amp;rsquo;s CTG Editor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created and supported a timeline-based scripting editor for cinematic artists, so they could do things like show/hide objects, change the time of day, or load/unload parts of the open world, over the course of a cinematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also owned a few other features relating to object spawners and batch editing game components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;game-jams&#34;&gt;Game Jams&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of games I worked on for a weekend or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://willridenourgames.itch.io/7-didnt-8-9&#34;&gt;7 Didn&amp;rsquo;t 8 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://j-a-rave.itch.io/our-friend-sloth&#34;&gt;Our friend Sloth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
