<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on J Rave</title>
    <link>https://jrave.dev/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on J Rave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 J Rave</copyright><atom:link href="https://jrave.dev/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/about/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/about/hello/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a game developer, software engineer, and all-around pusher of buttons.
I make games and tools for game developers, working in everything from C/C++ to TypeScript, from MEL to VBA.
I live in the Midwest US, where I grew up. I&amp;rsquo;m an agender person (they/them), a Zen Buddhist, and a hobbyist musician / cook / linguist / all sorts of things.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a game developer, software engineer, and all-around pusher of buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make games and tools for game developers, working in everything from C/C++ to  TypeScript, from MEL to VBA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in the Midwest US, where I grew up. I&amp;rsquo;m an agender person (they/them), a Zen Buddhist, and a hobbyist musician / cook / linguist / all sorts of things.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/about/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/about/projects/</guid>
      <description>Professional Spry Fox - Project Friendship Currently in development, a massively multiplayer cozy life sim. Creating and supporting workflows for artists, designers, and writers.
Torn Banner - Various Tools Mainly, I created and supported a proprietary tool called Submit Helper, a custom P4V tool designed to kick off preflight builds, manage Jira tickets, open/close code reviews, and anything else needed before things got tossed into the depot.
I also supported tool needs for animators, created a framework for building automated tests in UE5, and a few other things.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;professional&#34;&gt;Professional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spry-fox---project-friendship&#34;&gt;Spry Fox - Project Friendship&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently in development, a massively multiplayer cozy life sim. Creating and supporting workflows for artists, designers, and writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;torn-banner---various-tools&#34;&gt;Torn Banner - Various Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly, I created and supported a proprietary tool called &lt;strong&gt;Submit Helper&lt;/strong&gt;, a custom P4V tool designed to kick off preflight builds, manage Jira tickets, open/close code reviews, and anything else needed before things got tossed into the depot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also supported tool needs for animators, created a framework for building automated tests in UE5, and a few other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;volition---saints-row-2022&#34;&gt;Volition - Saints Row (2022)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first shipped AAA title - I worked on this from pre-production to DLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The realtime cinematics system was &lt;em&gt;my baby&lt;/em&gt;. In addition to implementing anything the cinematic artists needed, I also heavily supported the good folks in the lighting, VFX, and audio teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also the sole dedicated accessibility programmer, so I owned features like alternative control methods, blood &amp;amp; gore, subtitles, and some challenge level settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;volition---ctg-editor&#34;&gt;Volition - CTG Editor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created and supported a timeline-based scripting editor for cinematic artists, so they could do things like show/hide objects, change the time of day, or load/unload parts of the open world, over the course of a cinematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also owned a few other features relating to object spawners and batch editing game components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal&#34;&gt;Personal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;???&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Very early work-in-progress.&lt;/em&gt; Highly methodical visual puzzle game. Created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.love2d.org/&#34;&gt;LÖVE&lt;/a&gt;. Also developing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/j-a-rave/wuv2d/&#34;&gt;wuv2d&lt;/a&gt;, a library for developing games in Lua/LÖVE.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
