<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on J Rave</title>
    <link>https://jrave.dev/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on J Rave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 J Rave</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 23:52:46 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jrave.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brain Dump: Dialogue vs Conversation in Textile</title>
      <link>https://jrave.dev/blog/dialogue_4-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 23:52:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jrave.dev/blog/dialogue_4-23/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll try to reign this in as much as possible. Bear in mind this is somewhere between a design doc and a stream of consciousness.
Dialogue trees would be a wild way to speak to another human being. And yet, they&amp;rsquo;re ubiquitous in the world of video games.
They give the player ultimate agency over the information given in an interaction. The best dialogue systems in this style make it clear when a given option will move the conversation forward and give the player necessary information, or when it will give the player additional non-vital details.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try to reign this in as much as possible. Bear in mind this is somewhere between a design doc and a stream of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dialogue-trees-would-be-a-wild-way-to-speak-to-another-human-being&#34;&gt;Dialogue trees would be a wild way to speak to another human being.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, they&amp;rsquo;re ubiquitous in the world of video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They give the player ultimate agency over the information given in an interaction. The best dialogue systems in this style make it clear when a given option will move the conversation forward and give the player necessary information, or when it will give the player additional non-vital details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players need to buy in and voluntarily get more out of a conversation, or otherwise can breeze through an interaction and get back to the gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-can-we-do-better&#34;&gt;How can we do better?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When conversation &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; gameplay, simply following the heuristic isn&amp;rsquo;t nearly good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a visual novel, roleplaying game, or social deduction game, some of the most important gameplay revolves around speaking to the game&amp;rsquo;s characters. More importantly, &lt;em&gt;listening&lt;/em&gt; to them. But we&amp;rsquo;re still stuck on the rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick is to move away from the idea of dialogue, and toward conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-the-difference&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dialogue is performance. It exists for the benefit of an audience. Using a typical dialog tree, the player might be able to direct how much of a dialogue they see, or whether they see the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; version of the dialogue, but regardless they&amp;rsquo;ll be fed similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversation is a living thing. It exists for the benefit of its participants. In this case, both the player and the NPC would exchange information. What a character knows will be affected by what the player divulges, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-no-dialogue&#34;&gt;So, no dialogue?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes dialogue! But in Textile, we must make a distinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversation: Interaction between the player and one or more characters, driven systemically by character knowledge and motivation as well as player input. Mushroom and/or venom writing, per Emily Short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dialogue: Written exchange between two or more characters. Highly curated or non-generated; beeswax writing, per Emily Short.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
